<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>fmckeogh.github.io</title><link>https://fmckeogh.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on fmckeogh.github.io</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fmckeogh.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Rewriting FORTRAN Software In Rust</title><link>https://fmckeogh.github.io/post/shallow-water/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fmckeogh.github.io/post/shallow-water/</guid><description>github.com/rse-standrewscs/shallow-water TL;DR: Rewriting isn&amp;rsquo;t always bad but it probably was here, Amdahl’s Law is important and memory bandwidth is a potential bottleneck when doing many simple double precision math operations
Introduction As part of an Undergraduate Research Assistant Scheme in my first year of university I was tasked with parallelising a piece of shallow water simulation software written in FORTRAN by Dr David Dritschel of the Vortex Dynamics Research Group, under supervision of Dr.</description></item><item><title>Galileo constellation support on the Navio2</title><link>https://fmckeogh.github.io/post/galileo-navio2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fmckeogh.github.io/post/galileo-navio2/</guid><description>The Navio2 is a daughterboard for the Raspberry Pi 2/3 that allows you to use the Pi for robotics projects. It contains an array of sensors and IO, including IMUs, a barometer, and a GPS module. A u-blox NEO-M8N module to be exact. This GPS module was produced initially with a version 2 firmware which supported GPS and GLONASS, and later a version 3 which added Galileo support. Unfortunately the Navio2 board that I had only had version 2.</description></item><item><title>Convolutional Neural Network Bird Detector</title><link>https://fmckeogh.github.io/post/isitiabird/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fmckeogh.github.io/post/isitiabird/</guid><description>Now live at isitabird.mckeogh.tech EDIT: Also now written entirely in Go!
It’s been done many times already, but I needed a project to distract from my looming exam results. Like many others, I saw xkcd No. 1425 as a challenge, and in a few hours I had a working bird classifier, written in Python. New code available on GitHub.
There are many much better written articles online describing how it works, but essentially small mathematical functions, like neurones in a brain, make up networks that will take an input, apply those functions to it and produce an output.</description></item><item><title>Computer Vision for UAS Search and Rescue</title><link>https://fmckeogh.github.io/post/computer-vision-for-uas-search-and-rescue/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fmckeogh.github.io/post/computer-vision-for-uas-search-and-rescue/</guid><description>I am currently developing a multi-rotor unmanned aircraft system (UAS) to be used in search and rescue operations using object recognition to find a target and deliver a payload, e.g. to help an injured climber on traditionally inaccessible terrain needing to be dropped fluids, a torch, an insulating blanket and/or a flare to assist their survival and later rescue.
The onboard computer is a Raspberry Pi 3 with a Navio2 board.</description></item><item><title>RGB Motion Reactive Bluetooth Snowboard</title><link>https://fmckeogh.github.io/post/rgb-motion-reactive-bluetooth-snowboard/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fmckeogh.github.io/post/rgb-motion-reactive-bluetooth-snowboard/</guid><description>The weekend before we left on a winter holiday, I saw a bluetooth module and an Pro Mini on a breadboard and had an idea. What if I could control the lighting on a snowboard with my phone?
4 hours later, an LED strip and 5V regulator ordered, I set out to create a lighting system that I could install onto my board. Since I would be renting one and I couldn’t take any tools on the plane I had to plan carefully.</description></item><item><title>Long Range UAS</title><link>https://fmckeogh.github.io/post/long-range-uas/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fmckeogh.github.io/post/long-range-uas/</guid><description>My latest build is a Pixhawk Skywalker 1900 UAV. It has a wingspan of 1.9m, and uses a 4s 16000mAh battery.
The plane is outfitted with a 1.3GHz 800mW video transmitter, minimOSD and Skew Planer antenna.
My current record is a 3h14m flight completely autonomous, from take off to landing. I have been able to fly at 350M AGL drawing only 3.4 amps, showing at least 4 hours is possible on this platform with further work.</description></item><item><title>Aberystwyth University Robotics Beach Lab</title><link>https://fmckeogh.github.io/post/aberystwyth-university-robotics-beach-lab/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fmckeogh.github.io/post/aberystwyth-university-robotics-beach-lab/</guid><description>I was a student ambassador for the Aberystwyth University robotics department in 2014 and again in 2015. I demonstrated and talked to the public about the work I had done in the Aberystwyth Robotics Club.</description></item><item><title>Foam V-Tail UAV</title><link>https://fmckeogh.github.io/post/foam-vtail/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fmckeogh.github.io/post/foam-vtail/</guid><description>Here are some flight videos from Summer 2014.</description></item><item><title>My First Quadcopter</title><link>https://fmckeogh.github.io/post/first-quadcopter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fmckeogh.github.io/post/first-quadcopter/</guid><description>Recently, I found an old YouTube account of mine and along with it, this video. I made it aged 13 using my first quadcopter, a HobbyKing KK2.0 “mini quad”. I believe a member of the model club I attended had given me their old 72MHz radio and receiver which I used to fly this drone in the video.
Please excuse the cheesy music.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://fmckeogh.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fmckeogh.github.io/about/</guid><description>Etiam porta sem malesuada magna mollis euismod. Duis mollis, est non commodo luctus, nisi erat porttitor ligula, eget lacinia odio sem nec elit. Donec id elit non mi porta gravida at eget metus. Donec sed odio dui.
Donec sed odio dui. Nulla vitae elit libero, a pharetra augue. Nulla vitae elit libero, a pharetra augue. Praesent commodo cursus magna, vel scelerisque nisl consectetur et.
Nulla vitae elit libero, a pharetra augue.</description></item></channel></rss>